Welcome to the Qubic dot Net Wallet.
In this episode, we'll set up a new wallet from scratch — generating a seed, connecting to the network, and exploring the dashboard.
The Qubic dot Net Wallet runs as a native desktop application on Windows, macOS, and Linux.
It can also run in your browser using server mode.
This is the main interface.
On the left you have the navigation sidebar with links to every feature.
At the top is the seed bar — where you'll enter or unlock your identity.
Let's create a new wallet.
On the Home page, you'll see a Get Started panel and a Create New Wallet panel.
Click Generate New Seed.
The wallet creates a random 55-character lowercase seed.
This seed is your master key — it controls your identity and all your funds.
Click the eye icon to reveal the seed, and the copy button to copy it to your clipboard.
Important: Write down your seed on paper and store it somewhere safe.
If you lose your seed, your funds are gone forever.
Never share it with anyone.
Check the confirmation box and click Use This Seed.
Your identity is now active — you can see it in the top bar.
The truncated identity address is shown as a badge.
Click it to copy the full 60-character address.
Now let's connect to the Qubic network.
The wallet supports three backends.
RPC connects to a Qubic RPC server — this is the default and recommended for most users.
Bob connects to a Bob JSON-RPC node.
And Direct connects to a Qubic node via TCP — the most decentralized option.
Select your preferred backend and click Connect.
The current epoch and tick appear in the top bar, confirming you're connected.
Once connected with an active seed, the Home page becomes your dashboard.
At the top you see your full identity and QU balance.
Click Load Balance to refresh it.
Below that are Quick Action buttons for Send, Receive, Assets, QX Trading, and History.
The dashboard also shows your owned assets and any open orders on the QX exchange — giving you a snapshot of your portfolio at a glance.
That's it for getting started.
You now have a wallet with an active identity, connected to the Qubic network.