In this episode, we'll cover sending and receiving QU — the native currency of the Qubic network.
Click Send in the sidebar.
The From field shows your identity and current balance.
Enter the destination identity — you can type it manually, or select from your address book if you've saved contacts.
Enter the amount of QU to send.
The quick-fill buttons let you quickly set 10%, 25%, 50%, or 100% of your balance.
The Target Tick is set automatically.
The wallet picks the current tick plus an offset to give the network time to process your transaction.
Click Preview Transaction to review the details — destination, amount, and tick.
Now click Sign and Broadcast.
The wallet signs the transaction locally with your seed and sends it to the network.
You'll see the transaction ID and a link to track it in your history.
If the destination address isn't in your address book, the wallet offers to save it as a contact.
Next, let's look at Send to Many.
This feature lets you send QU to up to 25 recipients in a single transaction, using the QUTIL Send To Many V1 contract.
Add recipients one by one — each with an address and amount.
Or click Import from Text to paste a list of addresses and amounts, one per line, separated by commas or tabs.
If you have a vault set up, you can save the current recipient list as a named template.
This is handy for recurring payments — load a template, adjust amounts if needed, and send.
Review the total, sign, and broadcast — just like a single send.
Finally, let's visit the Receive page.
It displays your identity as a QR code.
Anyone can scan this to get your address.
Below the QR code is your full identity in a copyable format.
Click Copy Address to copy it, or Copy QR to copy the QR code image to your clipboard — handy for pasting into a chat or document.