The encrypted vault is one of the most important features in the Qubic dot Net Wallet.
It lets you store multiple seeds and an address book in a single encrypted file, protected by a password you choose.
Let's create a vault.
Enter a file path for the vault file.
Then enter the seed you want to store, give it a label like Main Wallet, and set a strong password.
Click Create Vault.
The wallet creates an AES-256-GCM encrypted file using Argon2id for key derivation.
This is the gold standard for password-based encryption.
Your vault can hold multiple seeds.
Let's add a second one.
Click Generate to create a fresh seed, give it a label — for example, Trading — and click Add Entry.
The vault now holds two identities.
You can switch between them instantly from the top bar dropdown — no need to re-enter seeds.
Now let's add some contacts to the address book.
Enter a label and an identity address, then click Add Contact.
Saved contacts appear as autocomplete suggestions in every address field across the app — Send, Send to Many, Assets, QX Trading, everywhere.
You can also save addresses on the fly.
After a successful transaction, the wallet offers to save the destination as a contact.
To secure your vault, click Lock in the top bar.
All seeds are cleared from memory.
To resume, enter your vault password and click Unlock.
If you enter a seed directly without a vault, the top bar shows a Save to Vault button.
Click it to create a new vault file or add the seed to an existing vault — right from the top bar.
You can also change your vault password at any time from the Settings page.