In this episode, we'll explore the Assets page and QX — Qubic's decentralized exchange.
The Assets page shows all tokens owned by an identity.
Enter any identity address and click Lookup Assets.
You'll see three categories: Owned assets, Possessed assets, and Issued assets.
For your own assets, you can directly place sell or buy orders, transfer to another address, view the order book, or manage rights — all from action buttons on each row.
Click Orders to view the live order book for any asset.
The asks and bids are shown side by side.
Click a row to pre-fill a trade.
Now let's move to QX Trading.
QX is the Qubic decentralized exchange, and this page gives you full access.
At the top, you see your open orders with cancel buttons for each.
The tabs give you everything you need.
Issue lets you create a new asset with a name, supply, and decimal places.
Transfer lets you send assets to another address.
Ask lets you place a sell order at your price.
Bid lets you place a buy order.
The total cost is calculated automatically.
And Rights lets you transfer asset management rights to a smart contract.
Below the tabs is the Market Overview — a table showing every traded asset with the best ask, best bid, depth, and spread.
Click Load to refresh it.