In this episode, we'll look at governance and smart contract auctions.
The Voting page lets you participate in community governance on the Qubic network.
Browse active proposals to see what's being voted on.
The Browse tab lists all current and past proposals.
Cast your vote on the Vote tab by selecting a proposal and choosing your option.
View results with progress bars on the Results tab — see how the community is leaning.
You can also create a new poll from the Create tab.
Set a question, define the options, and submit it to the network.
Now let's look at Smart Contract Auctions.
SC Auctions shows available smart contract slots on the Qubic network.
The Browse tab lists active auctions with their current bid status and time remaining.
The Status tab lets you check the status of a specific auction.
And the Bid tab lets you place bids to secure a smart contract slot.
Enter the auction details and your bid amount, then submit.
These governance features give you a direct voice in the Qubic ecosystem — from voting on proposals to securing smart contract capacity.