In this episode, we'll explore transaction history and log events — the tools for monitoring your activity on the Qubic network.
Transaction History has two tabs.
The Tracked tab shows transactions you've made from this wallet, with live status updates — Pending, Confirmed, or Failed.
Each transaction shows its current status.
Pending means the transaction has been broadcast but not yet confirmed.
Confirmed means the network has processed it.
And Failed means it didn't execute.
Expand any transaction to see full details — the destination, amount, tick, raw transaction data, and a Repeat Transaction button to re-send with the same parameters.
The All Transactions tab shows your complete history synced from the network — both sent and received.
You can filter by direction, type, or tick range to find specific transactions.
Now let's look at Log Events.
This page shows contract-level events for your identity — detailed logs synced from the Bob backend.
Each event has a type badge, amounts, and raw body data.
This is useful for tracking contract interactions like staking rewards, asset transfers, and DEX trades.
Together, Transaction History and Log Events give you full visibility into everything happening with your identity on the Qubic network.