In this final episode, we'll cover the Sign and Verify tool and the wallet settings.
Sign and Verify lets you cryptographically sign messages with your seed and verify signatures from others.
Type a message and click Sign.
The wallet produces a JSON object containing your identity, the message, and the digital signature.
Share this to prove you control the identity — useful for authentication or agreements.
To verify someone else's signature, paste the signed JSON and click Verify.
The wallet checks the cryptographic signature and tells you whether it's valid.
Now let's explore Settings.
Settings is organized into tabs.
General lets you switch between Light and Dark theme.
Connection lets you configure your default backend — RPC, Bob, or Direct — along with the server URLs and direct node address.
Transactions lets you adjust the auto-tick offset and enable auto-resend for failed transactions.
This is useful if your transactions often expire before being processed.
Labels lets you toggle remote label resolution, which shows human-readable names for known addresses like exchanges and contracts instead of raw 60-character identities.
Data lets you export or import your wallet database.
The database is encrypted with SQLCipher, keyed to your seed, so only you can read it.
And the Vault tab lets you manage your encrypted vault file — change its location, update the password, or disconnect from the vault entirely.
A few important security notes to close with.
Your seed is held in memory only during the session.
It is never written to disk unencrypted.
The encrypted vault uses AES-256-GCM with Argon2id key derivation.
And in server mode, access is protected by a one-time session token.
But prefer desktop mode when possible.
Never share your seed.
Qubic will never ask for it.
Anyone with your seed has full control of your funds.
Thanks for watching, and welcome to Qubic.